

Mahbub Zaman

Address: JA-28, North Badda, Dhaka

Contact: +880 1675736887

Email: mahbub.zaman04@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mahbub-zaman

Professional Profile

Over three years of experience support leaders in finance, commercial, and management roles. I was adept at developing and maintaining detailed administrative and procedural processes that reduce redundancy, improve accuracy and efficiency, and achieve organizational objectives.

Core Skills

- Bookkeeping
- Payment Voucher
- ERP Tally Software
- Digital Marketing
- Inventory Management
- Customer Experience
- Google Sheet
- Photoshop & Illustrator
- Data Entry
- Export/Import Documentation
- Microsoft Excel & Word
- HTML5 & CSS

Career Summary

Asset Developments & Holdings Ltd., Real estate developer

Junior Executive, Operation Finance (5 mos.)

Gulshan-1, Dhaka Jan 2020 - May 2020

Key Responsibilities:

- ERP Tally software usage for customer payment vouchers
- Posting transactions at General Ledger & Material Ledger
- Communication with banks & payees for financial transaction
- Maintain & update payment list, project index list via Microsoft excel
- Maintain payment document files

Junior Executive, General Accounts (3 mos.)

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

Key Responsibilities:

- Vehicle workshop store management
- ERP Tally software usage to make MRR & MTN for vehicle workshop spare parts & related material purchase & consumption
- Prepare monthly stock report in MS Excel by extracting data from ERP Tally Software
- Conduct fixed asset physical inventory that made from the outset of the year
- Manage scrap sale of abandoned material

Project Accountant, Project Finance (1 yr. 3 mos.)

Jul 2018 - Sep 2019

Key Responsibilities:

- Prepare petty cash, FR and adjust timely
- Prepare monthly attendance, late present, absents, and short leaves
- Prepare month-end stock reports
- Maintain store ledger & registers
- Communication with the supply chain for smooth material delivery
- Manage and ensure security of store material
- Other administrative, material management & project safety security works

Roshawa Group, Engaged in producing cotton yarn **Commercial Officer**, Export Division (1 yr. 6 mos.)

Banani, Dhaka Jan 2017 - Jun 2018

Key Responsibilities:

- Prepare shipping documents for local export against back to back L/C
- Prepare & compose G.S.P certificate & cash incentive certificate
- Prepare delivery order and proforma invoice
- Receive and endorse foreign import documents in the bank
- · Communication with bankers for payment, acceptance
- Cooperate import division in documentation
- · Other tasks assigned by management

Al-Arafah Islami Bank Limited

Intern, General Banking (3 mos.)

Pragati Sarani, Dhaka Nov 2015 - Feb 2016

Key Responsibilities:

- Account open
- Customer relationship management

Education & Qualifications

National University of Bangladesh

Master of Business Administration

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2018 - Present

- Concentration in Finance
- Exam Appeared

Bangladesh University of Business & Technology

Bachelor of Business Administration

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2012 - 2016

- Concentration in Finance
- CGPA 3.48

B.A.F Shaheen College

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2010 - 2011

Business StudiesCGPA 4.90

Language

- Bengali
 O
- English
- Hindi



Interpersonal & Other Skills

- Adaptability
- Emotional Intelligence
- Effective Communication
- Decision Making
- Organizational Awareness
- Problem Solving
- Teamwork

Declaration

• I do hereby declare that the statements mentioned above are true and correct.

Signature & Date